admiralty.co.uk 2019-06-29

# Privacy and Cookies | ADMIRALTY Maritime Data Solutions | ADMIRALTY

We are firmly committed to maintaining the security and confidentiality of personal information collected on this site. The purpose of this policy is to outline how the UK Hydrographic Office has established measures to protect your privacy and information rights. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. Please note this refers to your personal data (your name; address and anything that could be used to identify you personally).  

###  The contact details of UK Hydrographic Office Data Protection Advisor  and MOD Data Protection Officer: 

###  UKHO Data Protection Advisor 

Mr Leigh Raiment  

Hurd 3 

UK Hydrographic Office 

Admiralty Way

Taunton 

TA1 2DN 

leigh.raiment@ukho.gov.uk 

###  MOD Data Protection Officer  

Mr Martin Elliot 

MOD Data Protection Officer 

Ground Floor Zone D 

Main Building 

Whitehall 

London 

SW1A 2HB 

CIO-DPA@mod.gov.uk  

###  Why are we collecting or processing your data?   

Under the Data Protection legislation, we have a number of lawful reasons we can use (‘or process’) your personal data. When using [ admiralty.co.uk](http://www.admiralty.co.uk/) website users may be required to provide personal data, such as contact details (first name, last name, e-mail address, organisation). Where personal information is provided, this may be used to provide information on new products and services, except where a website user has indicated otherwise. In any case, personal information will not be passed to a third party. On written request, users may, view the information we hold about them and request that we update, correct or delete it. 

The Information Charter sets out the standards you can expect from the UKHO when we request or hold information, including but not limited to personal data about your enquiries.

###  When you consent to providing us with personal data, we promise: 

  * To only ask for what we need, and not to collect too much or irrelevant information 

  * To make sure you know why we need it 

  * To check the information we hold is accurate and up-to-date 

  * To protect the information and make sure nobody has access to it who shouldn't 

  * To make sure we don't keep it longer than necessary 

  * Not to make your personal information available for commercial use without your permission 

In return, we ask you to provide us with accurate information and inform us about any relevant updates, such as a new address. 

###  Our legal basis for processing your personal data:

Under the Data Protection legislation, one of the lawful bases to processing data is ‘legitimate interests’, which basically means we have a genuine and legitimate reason to processing data (e.g. to provide the product or service) and we are not overriding your fundamental rights or freedoms as an individual. 

The following are some examples of when and why we use legitimate interests in our work: 

  * Best interest. Processing your information to protect you against fraud and to ensure our websites and systems are secure. 

  * Personalisation: Where the processing enables us to modify, personalise or otherwise improve our services/communications for your benefit 

  * Analytics: To process your personal information for the purposes of customer analysis, assessment, profiling and direct marketing, on a personalised or aggregated basis, to help us with our activities and to provide you with the most relevant information as long as this does not harm any of your rights and interests.  

  * Research: To determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising and to develop our products, services and relationships with you. 

When someone visits our website, we use cookies to collect standard information about your general Internet usage. A cookie is a small piece of data that your Internet browser stores on your hard drive and is used when you visit the site to tailor your viewing and provide you with customised information. Only the information that you provide, or your preferences while visiting a website, can be stored in a cookie. For example, Our Site cannot determine personal details, such as your email address, unless you choose to submit them.  

We use Google Analytics to collect, analyse and review this personal data, from which, we are able to analyse online behaviour, and provide the best experience through improving our website. 

We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our websites. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it. 

We use this information to make each visit more rewarding and to provide us with information to help improve our service. We do not know (and do not wish to know) the identities of the individuals who visit our website 

###  With whom we will be sharing your personal data: 

###    

Personal  data will be no shared with any third parties.

###  For  how long we will keep the personal data, or criteria used to determine the retention period:

###   

We  will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including the purposes of satisfying any legal and regulatory requirements. 

Unless otherwise specified, we will hold your personal information: 

  * In accordance with our business needs, i.e. managing our relationship with you

  * Whilst we provide you with our services

  * In accordance with our contractual retention period

  * In accordance with any legal and regulatory requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. After the retention period, has elapsed all data will be destroyed securely in line with MOD data destruction policy. 

Under GDPR you have the following rights with regards to your personal data:  

  * The right to be informed about the collection and use of your personal data  

  * The right of access your personal data and supplementary information  

  * The right to have inaccurate personal data rectified, or completed if it is incomplete  

  * The right to restrict processing in certain circumstances  

  * The right to object to processing in certain circumstances  

  * The right to withdraw consent (where relevant)  

  * Right to complain to the information Commissioner  

At any one time, you have the right to be forgotten without undue delay Through these commitments, we will keep to UK Law, including the Data Protection Act 1998, General Data Protection Regulation 2018 and the Freedom of Information Act 2000. 

###  Transfer of personal data to other countries:  

This data will not be sent overseas.  

###  Automated decision making:

This data will not be used for any automated decision making. 

###  How we store personal data: 

This data will be stored in a secure government IT system.  UKHO protect its commercial sites and products from cybercrime by design, ensuring it and its customers can feel safe in the knowledge that UKHO hosts a stable and innovative cyberspace presence which the public can use safely. This statement is validated by independent testing in line with UK government policy. UKHO systems are also accredited in line with UK government Security Policy Framework (SPF) and in line with ISO27001. 

###  How to complain if you're unhappy:

If you're unhappy with how any aspect of this privacy notice, or how your personal information is being processed, please contact:  

UK Hydrographic Office 

Admiralty Way 

Taunton 

Somerset 

TA1 2DN 

We will acknowledge your complaint within five working days and send you a full response within 20 working days. If we can’t respond fully in this time, we will write and let you know why and tell you when you should get a full response.  

If you are still not happy, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO):  

Information Commissioner’s Office  

Wycliffe House  

Water Lane  

Wilmslow  

Cheshire  

SK9 5AF  

Tel: 0303 123 1113  

### 

__

  * ADMIRALTY Vector Chart Service (AVCS) is now available online to support shore-based decision making. Find out more… <https://t.co/z2ched0ga4>

About 9 days ago

  * Read our latest blog post to discover how marine geospatial data is key to unlocking the full potential of our ocea… <https://t.co/Bj8cONfPp2>

About 78 days ago

  * Further flag States approve ADP products as SOLAS compliant. An increasing number of vessels join most of the world… <https://t.co/vxQYuW6lcc>

About 134 days ago
